Curriculum Vitae

Ryunosuke "Ryan" Goto, M.D.

Resident Physician, Department of Pediatrics at the University of Tokyo Hospital

Email: <u>rgoto@m.u-tokyo.ac.jp</u>

Personal website: https://ryunosukegoto.github.io/



I am a Pediatrician at the University of Tokyo Hospital and Nagano Children's Hospital. After receiving primary and secondary education in the United Kingdom and the United States, I received my M.D. from the University of Tokyo in 2019. Much of my research has focused on the relationship between poverty and health as well as health and health services in humanitarian crises, and how policies can counteract the negative consequences of poverty and humanitarian crises. In particular, I'm interested in developing and applying machine learning-based econometric models to address these challenges and inform precision policy making. My work has been published in *The Lancet*, *JAMA Pediatrics*, and *Pediatrics*, among other journals.

Education M.D., Faculty of Medicine, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan

04/2013 - 03/2019

Monta Vista High School, Cupertino, CA, USA

08/2008 - 06/2012

Work Experience

Nagano Children's Hospital

Resident Physician, Pediatrics 10/2021 –

The University of Tokyo Hospital

Resident Physician, Pediatrics 04/2019 –

IBM Research

Research Intern 02/2019 - 03/2019

Explored possible applications of automated connected speech analysis in the detection of pragmatic language impairment in individuals with autistic spectrum disorder

United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East *Intern*

27/2017

07/2017 - 09/2017

Quality improvement and research on the dissemination and implementation of an electronic maternal and child health handbook application, e-MCH Handbook For more information on the e-MCH Handbook:

http://libopac.jica.go.jp/images/report/1000036631 02.pdf

CureApp, Inc.

Intern

12/2017 - 03/2018

Translated educational content of cognitive behavioral therapy for clinical psychologists (Beck Institute for Cognitive Behavior Therapy online training course) from English to Japanese

Foresight, Inc.

English Course Team 09/2014 - 01/2016

Wrote an English textbook and made online videos for junior high school students

Ongoing research

Social network analysis for prevention of social isolation 08/2022-

Adolescents of Ukraine During the 2022 Russian Invasion (AUDRI) Cohort 07/2022-

I receive generous funding from the Chernobyl-Fukushima Medical Fund for this project.

Social determinants of COVID-19: a mediation analysis of vaccination rates 3/2022-

Machine Learning Detects Heterogeneous Effects of Medicaid on Depression: Oregon Health Insurance Experiment 06/2021-

Heterogeneous effects of antidepressants on suicide 03/2021-

Longitudinal effects of the COVID-19 pandemic on the well-being of children 12/2020-

Other Activities

Maternal and Child Health Handbook Committee

Board Member

11/2019 -

A board member of a committee that aims to do research and make recommendations prior to amendments that will be made to the Maternal and Child Health Handbook in 2022

Publications

Peer-reviewed publications

Ryunosuke Goto*, Irina Pinchuk*, Oleksiy Kolodezhny, Nataliia Pimenova, Norbert Skokauskas. Mental health services in Ukraine during the early phases of the 2022 Russian invasion. *British Journal of Psychiatry*. 2022 Dec 2:1-6. (*joint first authors)

Ryunosuke Goto, Aurelie Piedvache, Mayumi Hangai, Yui Yamaoka, Mariko Sampei, Naomi Sawada, Yusuke Okubo, Kyoko Tanaka, Naho Morisaki, Mariko Hosozawa. Time trends in emotional well-being and self-esteem in children and adolescents during the COVID-19 pandemic. *Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Mental Health*. 2022 Nov 23;16:89.

Ryunosuke Goto, Yusuke Okubo, Norbert Skokauskas. Reasons and trends in youth's suicide rates during the COVID-19 pandemic. *The Lancet Regional Health – Western Pacific.* 2022 Oct 1;27:100567.

Irina Pinchuk*, **Ryunosuke Goto***, Nataliia Pimenova, Oleksiy Kolodezhny, Anthony P. S. Guerrero, Norbert Skokauskas. Mental health of helpline staff in

Ukraine during the 2022 Russian invasion. *European Psychiatry*. 2022 Aug 10; 65(1), E45. (*joint first authors)

Ryunosuke Goto, Roch Nianogo, Yusuke Okubo, Kosuke Inoue. Evaluation of Obesity Trends Among US Adolescents by Socioeconomic Status, 1999-2018. *JAMA Pediatrics.* 2022 June 21;176(9):937–940.

Yosuke Eriguchi, Xiaoxue Gu, Naoto Aoki, Maiko Nonaka, **Ryunosuke Goto**, Hitoshi Kuwabara, Yukiko Kano, Kiyoto Kasai. A 2-year longitudinal follow-up of quantitative assessment neck tics in Tourette's syndrome. *Plos One.* 2021 Dec 30;16(12):e0261560.

Ryunosuke Goto, Natsumi Matsuda, Maiko Nonaka, Yu Hamamoto, Yosuke Eriguchi, Mayu Fujiwara, Akane Suzuki, Yukari Yokoyama, Yukiko Kano. The Gilles de la Tourette Syndrome-Quality of Life Scale (GTS-QOL): A Validation in Japanese Patients. *Frontiers in Psychiatry.* 2022 Jan 3;12:797037.

Ryunosuke Goto, Yoko Watanabe, Ako Yamazaki, Masatoshi Sugita, Satoru Takeda, Masao Nakabayashi, Yasuhide Nakamura. Can digital health technologies exacerbate the health gap? A clustering analysis of mothers' opinions toward digitizing the maternal and child health handbook. *SSM-Population Health.* 2021 Oct;16:100935.

Ryunosuke Goto, Thomas Frodl, Norbert Skokauskas. Armed Conflict and Early Childhood Development in 12 Low- and Middle-Income Countries. *Pediatrics*. 2021 Sep;148(3),e2021050332.

Ryunosuke Goto, Ryo Inuzuka, Takahiro Shindo, Yoshiyuki Namai, Yoichiro Oda, Yutaka Harita, Akira Oka. Relationship between post-IVIG IgG levels and clinical outcomes in Kawasaki disease patients: new insight into the mechanism of action of IVIG. *Clinical Rheumatology*. 2020 Dec;39: 3747-55.

Seif Nasir*, **Ryunosuke Goto***, Akiko Kitamura, Sahar Alafeef, Ghada Ballout, Majed Hababeh, Junko Kiriya, Akihiro Seita, Masamine Jimba. Dissemination and implementation of the e-MCHHandbook, UNRWA's newly released maternal and child health mobile application: a cross-sectional study. *BMJ Open.* 2020;10:e034885. (*joint first authors)

Ryunosuke Goto, Miyuki Fujio, Natsumi Matsuda, Mayu Fujiwara, Marina Nobuyoshi, Maiko Nonaka, Toshiaki Kono, Masaki Kojima, Norbert Skokauskas, Yukiko Kano. The effects of comorbid Tourette symptoms on distress caused by compulsive-like behavior in very young children: a cross-sectional study. *Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Mental Health*. 2019 Jun 28;13:28.

Other publications

Ryunosuke Goto, Yoko Watanabe, Yasuhide Nakamura. JAPAN: Digitization of MCH Handbook and the socioeconomic disparity in health. *Japan International Cooperation Agency Technical Brief*. Jun 2022.

https://www.jica.go.jp/activities/issues/health/mch_handbook/ku57pq000028koi9-att/technical_brief_41.pdf.

Ryunosuke Goto, Anthony P. S. Guerrero, Mario Speranza, Daniel Fung, Campbell Paul, Norbert Skokauskas. War is a public health emergency. *The Lancet.* 2022 Apr 2; 399(1302):1302.

Akiko Kitamura, **Ryunosuke Goto**, Seif Nasir, Majed Hababeh, Ghada Ballout, Akihiro Seita. JORDAN: UNRWA's electric MCH Handbook application for Palestine Refugees. *Japan International Cooperation Agency Technical Brief*. August 2017. http://libopac.jica.go.jp/images/report/1000036631_02.pdf.

Japanese translation of: Cohn SL. Preoperative Evaluation for Noncardiac Surgery. *Ann Intern Med.* 2016;165:JITC81-JITC96. http://annals.org/data/journals/aim/935916/aitc201612060_japanese.pdf

Presentations and

Oral Conference Presentations

Talks

Ryunosuke Goto, Kosuke Inoue, Itsuki Osawa, Katherine Baicker, Scott L. Fleming, Yusuke Tsugawa. Machine Learning Detects Heterogeneous Effects of Medicaid on Depression: Oregon Health Insurance Experiment. Society for Epidemiologic Research (SER) Annual Meeting (International Conference), Portland, OR, United States. Scheduled June, 2023.

Ryunosuke Goto, Thomas Frodl, Norbert Skokauskas. Armed Conflict and Early Childhood Development in 12 Low- and Middle-Income Countries. American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) National Conference and Exhibition (International Conference), Philadelphia, PA, United States (virtual). October, 2021.

Ryunosuke Goto, Miyuki Fujio, Natsumi Matsuda, Mayu Fujiwara, Norbert Skokauskas, Yukiko Kano. Effects of comorbid Tourette symptoms on distress by compulsive-like behavior in very young children. 24th World Congress of the International Association for Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Allied Professions (IACAPAP) (International Conference), Singapore. December, 2020.

Ryunosuke Goto, Seif Nasir, Akiko Kitamura, Majed Hababeh, Ghada Ballout, Junko Kiriya, Akihiro Seita, Masamine Jimba. Dissemination and implementation of the e-MCH Handbook, the potential role of m-Health in improving health equity in a refugee setting: A cross-sectional study. American Public Health Association (APHA) Annual Meeting (International Conference), San Diego, CA, United States. November, 2018.

Invited Talks

Ryunosuke Goto, Akihiro Nishi. Social network analysis and network interventions in society, human development, and health research. *Eunice Kennedy Shriver* National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD) Social and Behavioral Sciences Branch Seminar Series. November 10, 2022.

Ryunosuke Goto. What changes can the electronic Maternal and Child Health Handbook bring to health care? An example from Jordan. 4th annual Maternal and Child Health Handbook Forum, Tokyo, Japan. October 8, 2019. An overview on the electronic Maternal and Child Health Handbook in Jordan and Palestine refugees

Ryunosuke Goto. Social common capital and health: from a global perspective. **Nikkei SDGs Forum**, Tokyo, Japan. May 9, 2019.

A presentation on the electronic Maternal and Child Health Handbook in Jordan and how it contributed to health equity for Palestine refugees

Volunteer Engagement

International Medical Volunteers Japan Heart

08/2018

Helped with perioperative and intraoperative care of pediatric patients requiring surgery in Wachet Charity Hospital, Myanmar

Daycare Center at the San Francisco Japanese School San Jose Campus 04/2010 - 06/2012

Organization of Special Needs Families

06/2011 - 06/2012

Worked with autistic children and received the Fremont Union High School District Board of Trustees Community Service Award for the work

Qualifications

TOEFL iBT 117/120

02/2023

United States Medical Licensing Examination (USMLE) Step 2 Clinical Skills 11/2018

Honors and Awards

Society for Epidemiologic Research Kenneth Rothman Travel Scholarship 06/2023

Awarded for the 2023 Annual Meeting

Ukrainian Psychiatric Association Dr. Stanislav Kostyuchenko Award 02/2023

Awarded to young researchers, doctors, or clinical psychologists who made significant contributions to psychiatric care in Ukraine

The University of Tokyo Hospital Department of Pediatrics Research Award 11/2022

Awarded the top researcher in the department

Donald J. Cohen Fellowship Program for International Scholars in Child and Adolescent Mental Health

12/2020

Awarded by the International Association for Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Allied Professions (IACAPAP) to emerging leaders in child and adolescent mental health throughout the world

The University of Tokyo Faculty of Medicine Dean's Award

01/2018

Awarded to the top three out of about 120 students in the Class of 2019, based on excellence in clinical rotations

The University of Tokyo Osamu Otsubo Fellowship

01/2018

A scholarship awarded to top students who aspire to receive medical education abroad

The University of Tokyo Go Global Scholarship

Autumn 2017 and Spring 2018

A scholarship awarded to top students to study abroad

Pigeon Foundation Scholarship for Aspiring Pediatricians, Obstetricians, and Gynecologists

04/2017 - 03/2019

A scholarship awarded to top medical students who aim to become pediatricians, obstetricians, or gynecologists

U.S. Clinical Experience

Neonatal Intensive Care Unit, Boston Children's Hospital (clinical clerkship) 05/2018 - 06/2018 (4 weeks)

Pediatric Critical Care Unit, Children's Hospital of Philadelphia (observership) 04/2018 - 05/2018 (4 weeks)

Pediatric Surgery, Children's Hospital of Philadelphia (clinical clerkship) 03/2018 - 04/2018 (4 weeks)